Why I would like to work with Transim

- I want to work in a fast paced environment on the cutting edge of web development.
- I want to improve my knowledge of web development best practices by working with talented developers.
- I would like to work for a company involved in engineering in order to leverage my background in math and physics.
- I would like to begin a serious career in web development because I find it rewarding and see potential for growth.
- I would love to relocate to Portland.

What I bring to the table

- I have a strong technical background in programming, founded on degrees in math and physics.
- I have past experience with PHP in the design and development of web applications.
- I have a working knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript and AJAX, from prior work in web development.
- I have a working knowledge of MVC patterns in web design, including knowledge of popular MVC frameworks like Rails and Django.
- I am a team player with strong communication skills, and I look forward to working with and learning from other talented developers.
- I have a background in computational physics.

Who I am

I am a fast learner with good problem solving skills and my head in code since grade school, when I discovered a BASIC interpreter on the family computer. After graduating, I worked as a programmer for an academic research group writing simulations, and I cut my teeth in web development by working with small startups. Before embarking on a serious career in development, I decided to challenge myself personally in new ways by joining the Peace Corps. After a lengthy application process and a year in service, the Peace Corps evacuated me from Liberia in August due to concerns about Ebola. Armed with many lessons in self-motivation and creative problem solving from the Peace Corps, I'm ready to resume a more technical career.

In order to become more competitive for technical positions and reacquaint myself with current web technologies, I have begun actively contributing to open source projects and building a web development portfolio. Check out my projects and contributions on my github account: https://github.com/MCGallaspy.

Michael Gallaspy

702.271.3266 - 5426 Wesleyan Ct. - Las Vegas, NV 89113 - gallaspy.michael@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/pub/michael-gallaspy https://github.com/MCGallaspy

Education

2006 - 2010 University of Nevada, Reno

BS in Mathematics BS in Physics

Employment

2013-2014

Peace Corps

Teacher, Liberia

- High school math and science teacher to rural Liberian students.
- Organized and taught teacher training workshops and supported extracurricular activities for students, including chess, math and gardening clubs.
- Lead training of new volunteers in cross-cultural interactions and teaching techniques.
- Worked with extremely low resources in a highly challenging environment requiring lots of selfmotivation.

2011-Present

Web Developer and Programmer, Self Employed

- Provide web development, programming and design services on a freelance basis.
- Contractual work with small start-ups.
- Includes web server maintenance and deployment.
- Includes programming in PHP, Javascript, Python and design in HTML/CSS.
- References available upon request.

2011 Desert Research Institute

Research Assistant, Reno, NV

- Developed numerical simulations of light scattering by atmospheric aerosols.
- Wrote highly-optimized simulations in C/C++, FORTRAN and MatLab.
- Prepared manuscripts for publication.

2009-2010

Engineering Computing Center

System Administrator, Reno, NV

- Oversaw deployment and maintenance of computer hardware and software for a computer lab.
- Included Windows and GNU/Linux enterprise servers and personal workstations.

Internship

2010

Undergrad Research Assistant Paid Internship – University of Nevada, Reno

- Designed, created, and tested a novel laboratory device for measuring pressure waves in a gas.
- Included design process from theoretical model, prediction of numerical results, and machining for the construction.
- Wrote a manuscript detailing the research capabilities and intended use of the device.

Experience and Skills

- Familiar with PHP, Javascript, jQuery, Python, Ruby, FORTRAN, Django, MySQL, HTML/CSS, C/C++ and Haskell.
- Experience with Linux systems administration (and I use it every day personally).
- Knowledge of OO design practices.
- Background in physics.
- Ich kann ein bißchen Deutsch sprechen, und wird gern mehr lernen.